[music]
I would like to ask you a question
whether you trust your laptop, your phone
or the smart TV that
you have at home, I think everyone in the
audience understands that
technology is increasingly penetrating
our lives, no one is surprised by the fact that
after work we can  turn on
food in the microwave for heating, that
cameras are watching us everywhere and analyzing our
actions, that our children are already playing
smart toys that are connected to
Wi-Fi, which transmit some data
to various servers, but do we worry
about this data if we have fears and what
if hackers attack our country and
take over our online media and
government sites, who should we
believe and that these fears remain
fears so that we live in some kind
of confidence that we are not being
deceived that we are not being watched, every
state should monitor  for its
cyber security should nurture
its own hackers who will protect
their state and Kazakhstan in this  no
exception, let's go back to the present,
that is, you read the news on the net and the
latest headlines are full of the fact
that the United States accuses Russia of cyber aggression
that China has already put
our industrial tibbers on stream that even
let's say so North Korea, which
would seem to be in isolation to the
technological  of progress, they already say
what exactly it produced, the land was attacked,
yes, you probably heard a lot about it,
which because of which the world suffered
billions of dollars in losses, and I want to tell you
in general who hackers are,
how they affect progress, why
Kazakhstan should build some kind of its own
defense to a cyber shield and  can we become
that country of correct hackers who
where we will live confidently and feel
safe, let's start with the first
question of who are hackers, that is, the world
we share good and evil
yin-yang black and white and the hacker
world, that is, there is the so-called  black
hacker white hacker that is, but they are
called by a different name, they are black hats and
white bread  that is, black hats, those
who are engaged in hacking for some kind of
profit, that is, there is blackmail for the sake of and
money has grown from your cards
for the sake of massive attacks, and so on, I think
many of you have come across this, but since
there is a black hacker, there is a natural
white hacker  white hats, that is, these are the
guys who are engaged in hacking,
find for the sake of some kind of self-affirmation,
curiosity, that is, after they
find a vulnerability somewhere, they
report it to the owner of the systems, and usually
these people wanted and help countries to complete
their protection, but in addition to these two
groups, there are  there are also other types of
hackers, that is, the same hacktivists,
you probably all heard about anonymous oh
yes, that is, even though vista are those who
hack for the sake of some idea of their own, that is, f
r the sake of freedom of speech for the sake of freedom of the Inter
et, then
here are the so-called violin dice for
this may be an unfamiliar word for you, you
all hackers think that these are just words
hacker violin dice these are those who themselves do not
write viruses themselves do not  they develop ryan
and they just buy it on various
forums before using some other people's
work, but it is they who steal your
social accounts on instagram
it is they who encrypt your computers
it is they who steal money from you, that is,
so that you understand
that a low-skilled simple
hacker is acting against you  that is, they are not real hackers yet,
there are so-called cyber
terrorists, that is, the last trend
is especially relevant in the Middle
East,
many traveler's checks are sponsored, that
is, such cyber groups have
unlimited budgets and they will hack
for the sake of some idea of their own, yes, there is polit
cal, religious and
Kazakhstan  unfortunately, it’s no exception, that
is, we fix hacks every day and
these hackers replace the main page and
publish some extremist
calls there, thereby they spread
their ideas and the last type
that we’ll talk about today is in
English called sponsors
hackers of those same cyber  troops  who
have unlimited budgets and
unlimited opportunities now we live at
a time when the one who controls
cyberspace will also control
our world, and therefore I now want to
tell you how I actually came to this myself
why I got carried away with hacking it all
starts here starts with a passion for
computer games to sit there  on the
Internet how can you do it for free
everything further is already interesting
programming yes how to write your own
game there how to write a small
program to distinguish the guys here
then everything smoothly goes to the
olympiads and after that it seems to me
that the line is going, that is, either you just
go there  on the path of a programmer on the path of a
system administrator yes, that is,
as long as you are trunks or you go
deeper, that is, you are curious you are
curious how another program works
you are curious what if you
insert another parameter here as
another developer thought
there how to hack your
school teacher's computer  yes and there  to
place some kind of not beautiful picture there, yes,
well, most likely it’s vulgar this childhood
, we usually posted it to you, but
let’s say it would seem that some kind of
harmless such jokes turn into
some kind of income, and now the hacker
becomes one of the first VKontakte
spammers because  that vkontakte then
had weak filters,
so you could safely
distribute rubber there a message and
now hacked Pavel Durov himself
because they didn’t check the code of your
game, by the way, on the world, many of you
played the farm before vkontakte, so
you know through such popular games a
hacker  hijacked a million accounts and
read a million rewritten and
that is, you want to go to the
next step and you and your
friend slider launch
a worm on mail.ru there that gives
you access to a million mail
accounts there and you can read it all
any here and  yes, and you are already here,
youthful maximalism comes to you, you
feel like a god, you understand
that you can do it there  something to control
some kind of interaction there 2 me
other people with other people and so
on and just at this moment and a person
chooses to that side, that is, one thing and
you do it for the sake of curiosity
for the sake of some kind of self-assertion and
then you report it to the owner about
this appearance that he fixed another
thing when you cross this line and
it becomes a blockhead theme black hats and
when you start extorting money when
you start stealing money from these people
and
you turn here maybe you
heard the words carter yes there  these are those
who just withdraw money from your cards
and hacking is primarily
curiosity, that is, what if I
do this, yes, and what if I
do it differently than the program was
calculated and in fact there is 1 hacker,
it was not those who  he cracked the
source code it was the first though and they
were social engineers i.e. they
found gaps in people's communications in people's
actions i.e. made it so
that he  it would have told you some information
when hackers started and this is how it
started and these young people are the
future and become who shot down and at least
once they become the very cyber
troops such were the defenders who
help their state build a
secure
infrastructure and now I want it  using the example of
two countries, here is the first country, this is
Israel, you all know that Israel has a
national idea, yes, this is
security, but few people know that Israel
is one of the main suppliers of
cyber weapons, that is, virus trojans,
an interception system for such
your calls, that is, you will not have time  fly to
them at the airport they monitor all
your social networks do who you
communicate with if you are in the dark net
yes if your passwords in the dark net are there from
your mail I saw these systems they
cost a million dollars and they are
really impressive, that is, they
work more than  100 investigators who
every day try to find the use of the suits of
your phones, then in this operation
system and besides that, they also
monitor the entire Internet for new such
ultrasound suits, buy them and add them to
their cyber weapon, that is, they understand
that
cyber attacks are the weapon of the future next
I would like to tell about the usa everyone must
have heard about the wikileaks leak
published was a cyber weapon leak
nbc  ru that is, it was probably the
biggest gift for hackers, some hackers
stole from other hackers and published
something on the net and what you can see here is
interesting, that is,
more than eight thousand documents were shown there that
explain how to hack this or that,
you can see there an
uzi suit magician  android here you are all the numbers
trust your antivirus but you should
know that you are in the middle of the name of
all popular antiviruses, that is, they
all bypass, that is, the same one on the
edge did bypass the antivirus, that is, it
will not be difficult for a hacker to bypass your antivirus,
so do not rely on it  something else is
interesting, I told you if you are not afraid
that your body is watching you  visor and
here in the upper left corner you can even
see the brand name of the TV before the
samsung g80 smart tivi,
so they had instructions on how
you can
even turn off the TV and
turn on the camera so that they don’t notice it and
listen to everything around your
space so  girls be
careful when you go half-naked to
cover but we like it here in
the lower right corner
you see 2048 mayor everyone played it yes I
didn’t play it either so you know how the
special services would develop special
games like this 2840 it’s 2048 which were
substituted and which got access to
your  phone, you understand that if a
person gets access to your phone, this is
all your correspondence, all your
location,
all that you do, that is, this is all your
personal life, it is always impressive that
billions of dollars have been spent on this and you
see what potential and that's one
hope you after that  also stand and
paranoid yet I
cyber attacks have already become the ideal
tool of current wars t  oh, they are
swift and effective in their
destructiveness, as a rule,
unfortunately they are anonymous, that is, you don’t
know where the attack comes from, that is,
hackers how to do it, they can set up
servers in another country and through
them and now cyber weapons are
equated with weapons of mass
destruction  that is, he equated it with a
gun mass defeat let's move on
shooting range Kazakhstan
yes what is the situation we have here we have a growing
rating of e-government
we all use both heads and z and so on
we
are building a start-up incubator there we
even have a vice prime minister  to
which is responsible to go in each
ministry there is a supervisor yes it seems
everything is fine but do you think we
are absolutely not safe there is such a
world rating called the cyber
readiness index it is compiled by the international
telecommunications institute and unfortunately we are in
this yandex in eighty-third
place yandex shows whether we are ready  we are
either not ready for cyber attacks unfortunately we are
absolutely  I’m not ready now, I want to
show you two cases of
our research from the technical details
that you yourself assessed what level of
cyber defense we have two years ago at one
of our conferences we demonstrated a
study it was a practical one at that
stage theoretically this is really
practical things we showed with the help of an
experiment how to  5 minutes you can
turn off the entire domain zone shop behind that
look we have a domain registrar system
the forging zone for this what does it mean
this is a system that manages all the
addresses of state institutions and
woof there the akimat court and so on, that
is, when you go through the sites you saw a
blouse  cue for
here there is a single system, unfortunately there
was a very childish use suit there, I
will not go into technical details
through which it was possible to
enter the system in five minutes, we will answer and
under the administrator, and here I am
only one click away from
deleting  ligovka z domain, that
is,
can you imagine these  all six, about six hundred
domains, if I could sleep, it would be possible to delete them,
and in order to restore all this, it
would probably take a
week, and that is, we would have a complete
black-out, that is, we would have
customs, the courts of schools and hospitals would
grow because everything  the second case is going through the
electronic government,
you may have recently
heard this, a month ago there was a noise about
the document management system, we published about it
, that is, so that you would have his
brother’s document system, this system that
goes through all orders, all correspondence and where
state bodies, that is, they are
used by ministries such attacks
so on and unfortunately there were
winters in that by sending just a girl and a
support service a
certain letter, you could get
access to the administration system and
get access to all the documents of
Constance government agencies, and that’s the saddest thing that
''
our employee who is studying in the second
year found this appearance  and Almaty University, that is,
it is not some kind of cyber in  oyska yes, that
is, you understand, it’s just an employee and he
could attack on the black market, that is, he
told us and so we reacted like this, but is
everything so bad, that is, can we
make you become one of the world’s
powers, that is, we have many
officials here  and the predators say that we
should become how to follow the path of india
china to nurture thousands of
programmers there and outsource everything but
let's admit that we will not be able to
compete there with millions of
programmers from india and china it's pretty
hard we have not such a large population
but what are we  we can do we can reach
our own hackers and it doesn’t need
so much that is, it doesn’t need to be done
for a million, we will have enough at least to
raise this one, if at least 100
people, that is, that person is enough
even if you look at India has millions of
programmers but  in the hacker field, let's say,
they are rather weak, we just
can fill a niche, especially since we
have a good potential in Kazakhstan, that
is, we have a good  we have a mathematical school
that is developing everywhere, and those
industries are so stormy, and now we
even brought cybersport to our academy,
and on the wave of this whole hype, we can
object to these people and
you can look at this slide in this
photo, one of the strongest hacker teams in the
central  asia i want to be sent this is
our team few of you know but this
team has been taking first
place at the international hacker
conference for two years now thanks for clapping
i.e. we are more known abroad than in
kazakhstan we are filmed there and the diode and
i.e. there are two-day
competitions there cyber  a training ground where an
imitation of a smart city is located where a
nuclear power plant stands there this is a smart
traffic light Internet banking and more than 10 and
hacker teams from all over the world
compete with each other and from who
will advance further talking about the potential I
’m saying that we have these guys here
they are not so  a lot and as you can see it's not
those nerds in thick glasses as they
used to see boats, that is, this
it looks pretty nice, but
unfortunately there are not enough of these people, that is, even
the guys want to go abroad everywhere and they
understand that they don’t go because they don’t
understand
that they are making history in Kazakhstan because they are trying to make call
astana one of those world cyber powers
to move their own  some kind of
research victories
what we should do I like the
expression
dear fuad bey you know him
who moved the spots to program in
Kazakhstan and he always says the battle
is for 1 person,
that is, we should look for those cyber
geniuses who have been fond of hacking since childhood from school
and  you have
to put them on the right path, that is, we
should not nurture thousands of
programmers there, we should find
precisely these talents who just need to find a
new generation that will replace these
guys and there will be more of them who
will be engaged in what will be built on
zhki drischet because boiling  you are not a
firewall, this is not a server, yes, these are people, these are
people who  they will defend, I want to say
that we are not a nuclear power yes we
have a very small population we have a
very small army part we are not at war
with our neighbors for a long time everyone in the world loved
but unfortunately cyber attacks can
come to us from any end
of the globe and they are already underway  we must
already be ready for this
and in order for us to live in peace we
must just find these people we
must support these people and they
will ensure our safety
thank you
[applause]
[music]