[music]
today is the best day of my life
today for the first time I smiled my
daughter smiled I'm not lying a minute ago
she smiled at me
between you butter nothing
words
and you can't
wait  perhaps to
be at work tomorrow
and upstairs was capricious and that’s enough I still don’t
want to listen
with money I lured me promised my salary
will be raised early work you will pay a
penalty the
contract of 5 million was honored that the
boss showed up for a day
yes I don’t give a damn in fact just one
disease is very serious no more
could refuse such a station everyone
caught a cold it really hurts the pub is
back and
[music]
I'm sorry that I didn't tell you after
that we'll talk about what we know cruise camera
[music]
hold it for you
how marshmallows from childhood I love
how you learned you know  it seems to me
that there is some kind of cosmic connection between us and
some kind of higher mind,
first they send me delicious rolls
dude kissed  and you punalu something
completely turn scary you still don’t
turn
happily stay in the head
you need it
fresh
in the morning from japan they brought it from puffer fish,
but the fact that puffer needs to be crazy and
poisonous, then I’ll lend you cheaper times
no, take it right, the ballerinas galloped up to the
guzyr if you
cooked the pate normally only once, this does not
mean that now you can be late
at all  now my critics liked my pate Mishkinsky
liked us help
counting what kind of husband it was there bread
did you like the water like this to say
that you don’t envy the
tail no one will answer that the puppy decided
that you will notice me better and I ed said
oh here it is like then  I propose a bet
if you are really better than me, you will accept without any
problems and a jester with a stitching a
puffer fish
she lived a lion a dog she is an enemy
one mil  a gram of her tetrodotoxin poison is
enough to kill a person fugu fish
is prepared only by the best chefs
who passed the exam and survived after
it because fugu does not forgive mistakes
[music]
every one that cooks there is the same
as crucian carp
[music]
great when we take fugu from Timur  you
cook eat if you stay alive then
I admit that you are the best I agree to the chef
you cook to go out although why the
night for a couple of a friend to cook at all do not
agree
write a will I omit
[music]
as
well
[music]
whether Anna andrevna mortar  muse equal
bottles sachets like a pharmacy
pulsator 10k I’ll tell you in short anna
andreevna
any when you also love that how do you
think
it dies
[music]
type
once again I heard that you spread
gossip I’ll fire without pletenie spreading I
’ll fire everything low do
n’t come on  come on, he
smells a grimy imp blacker than black,
eleonora andreevna is dying, he will fire him,
or everyone knows
[music]
you write a lot  that I
’ll win the question a little more and brim you’re
just a very versatile man you
found out about what the blue search for the city is for me, you
damn well
hear, and he also studied at a music school
in the violin class violinist karateka like
flax I’ll say you are like that I noticed but that’s
why  according to the book,
a beautiful cartoon with Nikita could
look like they had a jump and the kiss
didn’t go further let’s treat couples
[music]
let’s play
part
1  Milan Yes I ca
n’t wait so long I have a month left I
don’t know when cutting fish you have to be
extremely careful tetrodotoxin is
contained in milk and the cry of the skin and ovens
we start by skinning timur fugu
brought the music you don’t want to refuse before
it’s too late at best  a terrible poisoning awaits you, the
worst is modest and
quiet, and a memorial service is impossible as well,
and yet they work a sense of
victory from the sleeves of the ball
even sushi and Nikita
then understood
[music]
entrecote in British style we move twice
well, why didn’t the rump change its mind so young
that it will help you change your mind right
there’s nothing to lose you have nothing to lose for another thirty years,
God sees I wanted to ask you here
I was kind of cleaning up and didn’t beat that
gloves on her sleep killer Nikita what are you going to
do I attack this shirt got dirty
so I came in to wash and you what I
’ll try too maybe and then after me I’m not
not I and I can’t I can’t with a stain
on  walk in the hall and you can not
see you, I also can’t look at me,
but
[music]
Vova we are deep, they are in half at
which it’s a pity to waste a whole fish of your life I
agree to wipe it off for you, but with it
half is enough
[music]
breastplate
booze test
presentation to your gray hairs
Viktor Petrovich,
I suggest you be the first to evaluate your
dishes
[music]
toys lab
play a bottle talks about where, well, from the
team, however, I also have no
secrets
[music]
I'll do this on an old friendship
man cook well this mackerel
I can't handle .
ok how are you doing my advice about poop
yes thank you not a signal of champagne of the
best cessna at my expense
tyumen
there is a reason the
doctor is alive of course alive he is your
fugu nil
I replaced my piece of fillet with my own
[music]
[applause]
here
[music]
I don’t  I’m ready to take a sin on my soul I couldn’t even
afford to take such risks
I wouldn’t have happened, of course it wouldn’t have happened,
but only at first you would have become numb language I
[music]
thought for a long time I would like to then throw you
into a fever and start hotels after this
in order, then the coordination would have been broken,
speech paralysis would set in, I
wanted to, I took a male
well
[music]
yes, and then all
this
[music]
swimming
like a dog refueled that I was poisoned alive ringing
from the bark
how it all turned
out  feel 4 enema what do you
think of many 6 how did you get poisoned
that the wrong division of litas yeah yes I
did everything right just I was in such a hurry to
save your skin that I forgot space
gloves
[music]
[applause]
so
pr  leave
[music]
here
and
[applause] by the
way, formally
you won but the gift poisoned my
fish congratulations but it's a good voice
there is a bad one you're fired how why can't I
sleep and but the facts are fair two cool
chefs can't get along to the same kitchen
so tomorrow they give you being
in the cook claude model at least in appearance
why do I need this bull that he
poisoned me again and he didn’t infect you,
I explained to you and a year later
all the restaurants in Moscow were good for you granny
because he is me  in his youth, this one
scares around the house how much, that is, you will
save if you sign it now
you no longer need a good chef in a
restaurant
[music]
maria himself is not Dmitry Vladimirovich,
so maxim now you are a new chef
model
[music]
I'm the same form
don’t let me down thank you horror buy from him z
well as much as possible
[music]
hello do you know when he will be born
sorry imagine me as a gay chef
in mane he called congratulations I hope
everything will work out for you  me now my whole life would be
different everything will be different you know
bush max
I already in the sense of
multiplication they leave to sing in a week
eleanor offered me a place
managing directors I agreed
max
so it will be better
and you already
[music]
you are not
but
[music]
and
well  how life will be so frightened
to listen get cheer up
stop look
these fools Fedi canopy on the left
played
my lost ours clicked here
and this is what my mother listening to
[music]
like that all this time did not take no how
no stole a car grave
no no  stank of them then why was
this whole circus needed because I wanted you to
like it and for this you agreed with
my mother maybe it was for space
communication maybe weight and paid you what
are you talking about and
[music]
who came to us in the new chef-  cook
dmitry vladimir
i won't work for you i'm leaving for st. petersburg i
ask for a new chance sometimes given
once in a lifetime i understand vic hear .  to leave
I just can’t help but go with them you are
still young
wiki children their life can be a lot and the
chance is 2.1 that family is more important to you
sorry  the main
instructive
[music]
she taught us to be brave and not
to be afraid by calling which prepare us for life
helped us achieve our
goals no matter what
we will play for the wedding in two more than it’s
not too late to participate and where should we
rush for the whole life ahead I’m making a
speck of you  what where in general
health like flu words god came there
zolla
yes you mark where you celebrate
I don’t know in two months we have
a wedding banquet here me and the girls
speed course the girl will again be your
boss the
most important thing is that this story has a
happy ending  century agreed
to stay in Moscow
and I became a chef we will
work together again dreams come true
think
he technique
[music]
but  as it usually happens when
one story ends, another always
begins
[music]
[music
] and
[music]